Camino Losada Alonso

Full-Stack Developer

Specialized in the **MERN stack** (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js), highly focused on **best practices**, **clean code**, and **Agile ecosystems**. I never miss the opportunity to explore and use technologies and tools that prioritize achieving an **optimal user experience** above all. And how did I get here? After completing my biology degree and specializing in fish and aquariums, I joined a **startup**, an environment in which I grew immensely both personally and professionally, **reaching goals far from my comfort zone**. All of this fueled my desire to take on what has been my **greatest and most satisfying challenge**: **programming**.

Experience

Full-Stack Web Development

05/2023 - Present

Freelance

Development of web applications in **Agile** environments, adopting a **Sprint**-based approach to ensure **efficient** and **high-quality** delivery: participation in **planning**, **review**, and continuous improvement **retrospectives**.

Rigorous version control and CI/CD workflow management, overseeing all code through workflows, unit testing, and integration testing to ensure clean and sustainable code. Monitoring key aspects such as accessibility, good practices, SEO, and performance.

- ~ LINKLIST app
- ~ TICKET-IN app
- ~ BRETARO app

Aquarist

Aquarium Barcelona & Aquadec Aquariums

11/2021 - 04/2023

Experience in the care and **well-being** of aquatic life, attending to each and every **detail** that makes it possible. Projects coordination.

Aguaponics operations & Communication

Green in Blue (before Aquapioneers)

12/2018 - 11/2021

Acomplishments:

~Brand Identity and Community Building

Creation of the **brand identity** and product from scratch, enabling Green in Blue to establish a strong **presence on social media**. This effort has allowed the company to build a prominent aquaponics **community** in Catalonia and Spain, gaining remarkable international recognition within the sustainability ecosystem.

~Education and outreach about aquaponics

Creation of theoretical-practical educational materials and the delivery of courses and **workshops**.

~Biotechnology and Production

Strategic planning and involvement in the design of facilities, selection of cultivated products, and their ultimate destination.

Education

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT Program

ISDI CODER

01/2023 - 05/2023

Approximately 1000 hours dedicated to practical programming in a **collaborative Agile environment**, subject to demanding **deadlines**.

Bachelor's Degree in Biology & MSc in Aquaculture

Universidad Santiago de Compostela

09/2012 - 07/2019



Barcelona

635014101

🔀 camino.losada.alonso@gmail.com

in in/caminolosadadeveloper

github.com/caminolosada

Skills

~FRONT-END & BACK-END

JavaScript · TypeScript · HTML5 CSS/SAAS · BEM · Styled-Components · React · Redux Vite · Axios · Netlify APIRest · Angular

Express.js · Node.js · MongoDB Mongoose · Postman · JWT · Joi validation · Render

~TESTING

React Testing Library · Jest Vitest · Supertest · TDD Mock-Service-Worker · MongoDB-Memory-Server

~BEST PRACTICES & CLEAN

Git · GitHub & Actions · CI/CD NPM · ESLint · Prettier Debugging · SonarCloud · Figma DevTools · Lighthouse · Trello Agile

~LANGUAGES

Spanish · Galician Native

English · French · Catalan Working Proficiency

~EMOTIONAL SKILLS

Empathy · Meticulousness Perseverance · Resilience Responsibility · Autonomy

Recognition

Finalist in the Jump2Digital
Hackathon, November 2023 (+100
participants)